In this, so we go ahead and we set up the learning problem.
We specify the size of the images,
that's determined by the SVHN, dataset itself.
We specify the size of the Z Vector.
This is just a hyper parameter that you can play with,
100 seems to perform perfectly well,
and it's also reasonably computationally cheap.
And then we set the learning rate.
The learning rate for Adam for GANs seems relatively stable across tasks.
Here we're using .0003.
For image net, I found that basically the same learning rate works really well,
except that I changed the 3 to a 4.
And that's all the more that I had to change for that task.
So, this setup is somewhat portable from one task to another.
This is the cell where we actually call most of the computation.
So, most of the time that you run the notebook,
you'll spend most of your time watching this cell execute.
We allocate the dataset,
we configure the batch size to be 128,
and we ask the model to train for 25 epochs.
During the debugging stage,
you might try dropping that to like 2 epochs.
At the end of the training process,
we pull out the list of accuracies over time and we get some of the last samples.
We go ahead and we plot the learning curves,
showing how the accuracy improves on both the training set and the test set over time.
After you go ahead and actually run your notebook,
once you have everything implemented correctly,
you should find that the test accuracy peaks at around 69-71 percent
There's a lot of randomness in this notebook and we don't
actually use random seeds anywhere.
So, you don't always see the same results.
It is possible to make it deterministic by seeding everything.
I personally like to avoid doing that because when you move
to real world problems where you have to use things like
asynchronous training and cues that load your data,
it's more or less impossible to make those deterministic anyway.
So, I like to on even the small problems where it's possible to make them deterministic,
I like to have people get used to the randomness that's
inherent to working with deep learning on larger datasets.
But you should pretty consistently see a test accuracy above 68 percent or so.
At this point, you're probably wondering how well we're doing compared to other methods.
One baseline we can look at is there was
a NIPS 2014 paper on semi-supervised classification
of SVHN and using variational methods.
They used the same number of labels, 1,000 labels,
that we use in this notebook,
and they got 64 percent accuracy.
If you take the same model that we have here and you rerun it with all the labels,
I get above 80 percent accuracy pretty fast.
And if you train it for longer,
you might actually get better than that.
I didn't actually run it for very long.
There are other architectures that are larger than
the ones in this network that obtain much higher accuracy,
at least 98 percent accuracy and I'm not actually sure
what the state of the art is for the fully supervised version of this task.