The next part of this notebook for you to do,
is to actually implement the simultaneous gradient descent that we'll use to train again.
In the previous DCGAN project,
we provided this part for you.
So now you get to learn a little bit more
about some of the nuts and bolts of building the GAN.
First, you'll need to get a list of all the weights and biases for the generator.
And then separately, get a list of all the weights and biases for the discriminator.
Each of those sets of parameters,
those for the generator and those for the discriminator,
will have different updates.
So you need to keep them apart from each other.
Next, you'll use Adam to propose an update for each of the players.
Simultaneously, each of these updates will be called and each update
will minimize one player's cost with respect to that player's parameters.
You should store these update opts as d_train_opt and g_train_opt.
Finally, we include a shrink_lr variable,
where we change the learning rate.
We'll call this at the end of each epoch to make
the learning rate gradually decrease over time.
You do not actually need to implement anything in the GAN class itself.
This just calls the functions that we've implemented earlier to set up the loss function,
set up the optimizer and so on.
And, it's just a place where we glue together a lot of the pieces that we built earlier.
You don't need to implement anything in the view sample's function,
this is just some code that we use to plot the samples and show them to you later on.
You don't need to implement anything in the train function, either.
We'll go ahead and run everything for you in here.
This is the place where we take all the pieces that you built and we glue them together.
I'll walk through a little bit just to explain what's actually going on.
One thing we do is we set up a saver that will
actually write the variables that you learned to a checkpoint.
If you'd like to take your training model and go and do something else with it,
after this notebook is done,
this will allow you to do so.
You could do something like go and see if you can
make adversarial examples for your classifier.
Or, you could use it to transcribe real photos of address numbers in images.
Next we make one copy of Z that we keep the same throughout the training process so,
that every time we plot the samples,
we're using the same Z values and any changes that you see from one epoch to the next,
are due to learning rather than sampling different values of Z.
We make a tensorflow session in order to run this particular experiment.
Then we initialize all of the weights and biases in the network.
We iterate for a predetermined number of epochs,
while you're debugging you might want to change this to a smaller number but at the end,
we give you enough that you can see a nice learning curve.
Overall it should take less than 25 minutes to run the whole thing.
Once it's ready to run,
we print out the epoch number,
so that you can get a little bit of a progress indicator in the notebook,
during this relatively slow part of the notebook,
this cell is where most of the time is going to be spent.
When we compute the training error,
there is a little bit of a subtlety because
different mini batches can be different sizes.
Most of the mini batches are going to be size 128,
but the number of examples in the training set is not divisible by 128.
So, the last batch of every epoch will be a different size,
because of that we actually need to compute the training accuracy,
keeping track of the fact that there
is a different number of examples in each mini batch.
For each step of training,
we grab an X value or Y value and a label mask from the data set.
If you wanted to build a really serious application,
this is one of the few places where this notebook is actually simplifying things.
In reality, you'd want to use a tensorflow Q,
to be able to read this very quickly in an asynchronous fashion.
But for the purpose of this SVHN problem,
it's fine to just iterate over the num pi variable like this.
Next, we generate the random noise for the input to the generator and num pi.
This is one of the other few places where
the notebook has simplified things a little bit,
compared to what you do for a real application.
For a real application,
you can actually just use a tensorflow random number generator
that would happen on GPU rather than NCPU.
We go ahead and we call the d_opt variable that you made as well as the g_opt variable,
both simultaneously to optimize
each player's cost with respect to that player's parameters simultaneously.
We just feed in all of the data that we pulled for
this iteration and run it through those optimization rules.
At the end of the epoch, we shrink the learning rate
so that we'll use a smaller learning rate on the next epoch.
We print out the training accuracy so that you
can get some idea of how well you're fitting the training set.
When you look at the training accuracy values that we print out,
there is two things you should keep in mind;
One is that we're computing the train accuracy only on the label examples,
we ignore the labels that are thrown away using the zeros and the label mask variables.
We do that so that you can see how well you're
fitting the examples where the labels were provided,
and not get distracted by how well you're
magically guessing the labels on the unlabeled training examples.
One other thing to keep in mind about the training accuracy variable that we print out,
is that it's updated on the fly during the learning process.
Every time we load a mini batch for training,
we keep track of how many examples were correctly
classified at the moment that we actually trained on them.
Over the course of a single epoch,
the model will actually improve.
It will do better at the end of the epoch than at the start of the epoch.
This training accuracy variable that we print out,
is an average over the performance throughout the entire time of the epoch.
So if we looked at a snapshot of the model
at the end of the epoch at the time we actually print this number,
it's accuracy at that point in time would be
slightly higher than the accuracy that we print,
just because the accuracy we print is
an average that looks backwards in time a little bit.
That might confuse you if you weren't aware of it,
because sometimes you'll see that
the test accuracy is actually higher than the train accuracy,
that's because the test_accuracy is computed instantaneously and
the train_accuracy is averaged over the course of training on a whole epoch.
After we finish training on epoch,
we iterate through the whole test set and we compute the accuracy on the test set,
just so that we can add that to our learning curve
and see how much we were over fitting over time.
We also spit out some samples that came from the generators,
so that you can see how the samples adapt over time from one epoch to the next.
And at the very end of the epoch,
we store the accuracies that we
computed in these lists that we'll use to make a plot later on.