All right, now it's time to go through the solution of the semi-supervised GAN
on SBHN Notebook.
We had you implement the global average pooling layer of the discriminator.
This just needs to take the average across
the spatial dimensions of the last layer of features.
We can take an average by using the reduce mean app.
And the most important part is that we just specify the axes to average over.
Axis 0 is the batch,
access 1 is the height,
access 2 is the width,
and access 3 is the channels of the feature map.
So, we want to take the average over access 1 and access 2,
to get rid of those spatial dimensions.
The next thing that we had you implement was the logits
for the different classes of the classifier.
And this part, there is actually
a decision that you could make about how you want to design the model.
We want to have a total of 11 different class probabilities,
and we represent that using a softmax.
One thing that's interesting about a softmax is that it's over parameterized.
The softmax normalizes itself so that it always has an output that sums to 1.
That means if you know the probabilities of the first 10 classes,
the 11th class is just one minus those first 10 probabilities.
In terms of the logits,
this means that you can set one of the logits to zero,
and the other 10 logits can control
the probability distribution over all 11 classes perfectly fine.
So, you have a choice of whether you want to actually have
a map mall that outputs 11 values,
or a map mall that outputs 10 and then set the extra one to zero.
We actually implemented both both versions so that you can see how they both work.
So, here we just say that we're going to pay attention to
this extra class switch to decide whether we should output 10 values or 11.
The next thing that we had you implement is the logits for the Sigmoid value.
We start off by remembering that the softmax needs to
represent a distribution over the 10 real classes and the one fake class.
The way that it does this will change depending on whether we've
decided to pursue the 11 class softmax,
or the 10 class softmax strategy.
If we're pursuing the 11 class softmax strategy,
then we need to actually split into two sets of logits.
We have 10 different logits giving us the distribution of the real classes,
and then we have one extra logit for the fake class.
And all of those actually come out of
the map mall and all of them are independently parameterized.
If we decided to only do a 10 class map mall,
then we can actually just take the output of the map mall,
and that gives us our largest for the real classes.
We also just hard class the logit for the fake class to zero.
And then the normalization of
the softmax will decide how much probability mass gets assigned to the fake class.
We want to actually compute
the log-sum-exp of all of the logits corresponding to the real class,
and then subtract off the logit corresponding to the fake class.
When we do this log-sum-exp,
we're going to subtract off the max like we described in
the trick for numerical stability up above.
And then we need to add that max back on later so that we don't change the final result.
We want this expression to be algebraically equivalent to the naive log-sum-exp.
But we just want it to be rearranged into that numerically stable form.