All right everybody. I'm excited for this notebook.
This notebook is all about semi supervised learning with GANs.
A lot of the time people ask me what are GANs actually good for.
You can use them to make all kinds of pretty pictures and so on.
But do we actually need pretty pictures to solve different engineering tasks?
And it turns out that they're actually useful
for a lot of other things besides just making pictures.
One of the things that's the most obviously useful to
most people is that you can use GANs for semi supervised learning.
What semi supervised learning means is that we still want to
train a classifier like we used to do with supervised learning.
But when we train a classifier with supervised learning,
our training set had both input examples like images that we're going to
represent with the letter X and output labels that we represent with the letter Y,
where we'd say for example that an image of a cat is a cat,
an image of a dog as a dog,
or an image of a handwritten digit is either 0,
1 or 2 or so on.
What happens if we don't actually have labels for all of our inputs and
we have to actually be able to learn from something that's just
an image and no information about what category it's in?
That's where GANs come in.
Before when we had a classifier that just takes an input X and gives you an output Y,
we had to train it by telling it specifically,
here's an input X and you need to produce
this specific value Y every time you see this input value X.
With GANs, we can take the discriminator and
we can turn the discriminator into a classifier.
For this notebook we're going to look at the Street View House Numbers data set.
And we're going to train a GAN to classify images
of digits that are photos taken by the Street View car.
There are 10 different digits, 0 through 9.
And for the GAN framework we're going to take
the discriminator and turn it into an 11 class classifier.
The first 10 classes are the class of real images of the different digits 0 through 9.
And then the eleventh class is the class of all fake images.
Because this discriminator gets to learn
inside the GAN framework instead of just learning as a classifier,
it has three different sources of information that it can draw from the training process.
The first is it actually gets to look at real images,
and retell it the label for some of those images.
But then we also have real images where we don't have a label.
On those, all that the classifier learns is that they're real.
It should try to maximize the sum of the probabilities of the different real classes.
But it doesn't know which one it should boost for any particular image.
And then finally, it should learn to reject fake images.
So it gets to train on three different things,
labeled images, unlabeled images,
and completely imaginary images.
That means you have a lot more inputs that we can use to train our classifier
than we would normally have if we were restricted to using only labeled data.
Because we get all these extra inputs,
we can get much lower error and much higher accuracy on the test set than
if we had to rely exclusively on inputs that we had been able to obtain labels for.
All right so let's dive in and look at how we actually build this semi supervised GAN.