Next, we had you implement the loss for the discriminator.
This is divided into two different parts.
The first part is the unsupervised part that I've highlighted here.
The unsupervised part, is divided into two different terms.
One is the loss on the real data,
and the other is a loss on the fake data.
In both cases, we're dealing with a binary classification problem.
So, we use the Sigmoid Cross entropy app to compute the loss.
For the real data, the labels are all ones
because we want to say that all the real data is real.
And, for the fake data the labels are
all zeros because we want to say all the fake data is fake.
In both cases, we just plug in the logits that we
computed up above using that log-sum-exp trick.
We chose these logits up above so that if you take the Sigmoid of them,
they give you the probability that the data is real rather than fake.
So, they're the correct thing to use here for
this binary real versus fake classification problem.
The second part of the loss for the discriminator is
the supervised portion of the semi-supervised learning algorithm.
Here, we actually take the cross entropy in terms of
the softmax between the labels for which class is present,
and the logits output over all the different classes.
One really important thing here is we need to remember to actually pay
attention only to the labels
that the label mask tells us we're allowed to say we're using.
We get the cross entropy for each example in the mini-batch.
And then we multiply by the label mask to make sure that we zero
out the cross entropy for any of the examples where we're supposed to ignore the label.
Then we want to take the mean cross entropy,
but we can't just use the tf.reduce_mean app,
because there is a mini-batch full of 128 examples here.
But most of them in an average mini-batch,
maybe even none of them,
have a label mask of one.
Instead, we get a different number of
labeled examples that we can actually use in each mini-batch.
So, we've got to explicitly compute
the numerator of the mean by
multiplying the label mask by each of the individual cross entropy switch example.
And then compute the denominator of that mean
by adding up the number of ones in our mini-batch of label masks.
Finally, there's one other little trick going on here.
If we have a mini-batch where nothing is labeled,
and here we're using so few labels that
a lot of our mini-batches are completely unlabelled,
we'd end up dividing by zero,
if all we had was this reduce sum here.
So, we take the max between the sum and one.
If the sum is zero,
then we divide by one,
and that doesn't actually change the value from the numerator.
So we either get a numerator of zero over one,
or we get a numerator of the sum of
all the cross entropies divided by the number of cross entropies we added up.
After we've computed both the supervised loss and both terms of the unsupervised loss,
we add all three of them together to get the complete loss for the discriminator.
Next we use the feature matching loss for the generator.
In statistics terminology, when we take a bunch of statistics from
one dataset and a bunch of statistics from
another dataset and we ask those statistics to be similar,
that's a learning technique called Moment Matching.
So, each of the statistics that we extract is called a Moment.
Here, the moments are
just the average values of features from the last layer of the discriminator.
First, we compute the moments on the data set itself by taking
the mean across the mini-batch of
all the features that we pulled out of the discriminator.
Next, we compute the same moments in the same way
but for the distribution of values that come from the generator,
rather than from the training dataset.
Finally, we compute the mean absolute difference between these two sets of moments,
and we use that as the loss for the generator.
That will encourage the generator to make sure that all of the feature values and
the discriminator have approximately the same average value,
regardless of whether the discriminator is run on the input or run on generated samples.
Over time, this will force the generated samples to become very
similar to data samples and have all of the statistics be the same.
If any of the statistics don't match,
the discriminator can learn to pay attention to
different statistics in order to find the difference between the two distributions.