The model_input's method is
some fairly boilerplate code that sets up things like input's real,
where we feed the actual images that come from the data set.
Input Z where we feed the random noise that we use to guide the generator and Y,
where we load the labels that specify
which of the ten digit classes each of the examples belongs to.
And a placeholder for the label mask,
where we specify which of the examples we should
actually allow ourselves to use the label on.
You've already done a notebook on implementing DCGANS.
So, you've already seen how to build a generator and a discriminator and so on.
Because of that, we're not going to ask you to build the generator
for us via chat and or for this semi-supervised learning task.
You can see here, that is a fairly simple DCGAN style generator,
using batch normalization and convolution transpose to start out with a noise vector,
reshape it to a convolution feature map,
and go through several rounds of convolution transpose to get a larger and larger image,
with fewer and fewer channels until eventually,
we output a 32 by 32 image with
three different channels for the colors red, green and blue.
And at the very end of the generator network,
we use a hyperbolic tangent function to
squash the values to negative one and positive one.
The discriminator network is really the most important part of this whole notebook,
because we're doing semi-supervised learning.
Our goal in semi-supervised learning is to make
a really good classifier that generalizes well to the test set,
even though we don't have many examples.
And the discriminator network,
is that model that we're going to train.
It's now a multi-class classifier.
So let's look at the discriminator net in a lot of detail.
We begin with a basic discriminator net that's really
focused on the DCGAN style of discriminator model.
We use convolution and batch normalization.
We don't ever use any Max pooling or average pooling, or anything like that.
Following the recommendation from the DCGAN paper,
we don't use any batch normalization in the first layer of the discriminator.
If we did that, it would be hard to make sure that
the pixels coming out of the generator have the correct mean and standard deviation.
As we go deeper in the network,
we do actually use batch normalization in a lot of places.
One thing you'll see, is that we don't ever use pooling to
reduce the size of the feature maps anywhere in the network.
Instead, we use convolution with a stride of two.
That's one of the recommendations from the DCGAN paper,
that originated in a paper called,
"The All Convolutional Net."
Another important aspect of this discriminator net,
is that we use dropout in several places.
We actually use dropout even on the very first convolutional layer.
But we also use dropout in other layers throughout the network.
The reason that we use dropout a little bit
more frequently here than in some of the other models,
is that dropout is a regularization technique.
It helps to make sure that the test error is not too
much higher than the training error for a classifier.
And, because we're working with only 1,000 labeled examples here,
it's really important to reduce the amount that we over fit,
that's going to be the biggest challenge that we're facing,
so we use lots of dropout all over the place.
We also see that we implement leaky relus everywhere.
We can build these by taking the maximum between
Alpha times the input and the input itself.
If you think about it, whenever the input is positive,
the positive version is going to win the max and get passed through.
Whenever the input is negative,
scaling the input down by Alpha will bring it closer to zero so make it greater,
and that means that the scaled negative input will win the max and get passed through.
So it will have a slope of Alpha,
rather than a slope of one,
in terms of a function of the input.
The reason that we use these leaky relus everywhere,
is that they always have a gradient that gets passed down to the layer below.
That gradient needs to propagate really cleanly through the discriminator,
because the gradient of the discriminator is the learning signal for the generator.
Layer seven of the discriminator is particularly interesting in this architecture.
We're going to use a loss function called feature matching,
that was invented by Tim at OpenAI.
The basic idea of feature matching,
is that we take some features from a hidden layer of
the discriminator and we make sure that the average feature value on
the training data is roughly comparable to
the average feature value on the data generated by the generator network.
Because we're going to take the average of different features,
we want to make sure that
the average feature value can
change when you move from one kind of data to the other kind of data.
Because of that, we don't use batch normalization on this layer.
Batch normalization subtracts off the mean of every feature value,
and then adds on an offset parameter that it learns essentially a bias parameter.
Because batch normalization goes ahead and sets
the means to be exactly equal to its bias parameter,
that means that these feature values would all get set to just have that particular mean.
And then the feature matching loss,
where we look at the difference in means of the features in the two different settings,
we're not actually going to be able to find any difference at all.
So when we get to this particular layer that we're going to use as those features,
we can't use batched norm,
or it will throw out our learning signal.
Tim got around this by using weight norm,
it took a little bit of careful coordination of the design of
the initialization of all the weights to make that weight norm network work really well.
To avoid the code complexity that we
need for the data dependent initialization that Tim used,
we're going to simplify things a little bit by using batch normalization in most places.
And then just not
using any kind of weight normalization or batch normalization or anything like that here.
But, if you'd like to learn about weight normalization and how that works,
you should definitely go read the weight normalization paper.
Another technique that works really well for convolutional classifiers,
is global average pooling.
In global average pooling,
for every feature map,
we take the average over all of
the spatial domain of the feature map and pass through just one value.
So, before we get to this layer,
we have a tensor that is batch size by height,
by width, by number of channels.
And we're going to take the average over the special dormain and
return just a tensor that is batch size by number of channels.
And that will give us a lot of invariants to translation,
if a digit appears in the image in several different locations,
we'll throw that location information out,
because we've averaged over all the different spatial positions.
Now we get to the point where you will implement the actual classifier.
You should add some kind of fully connected layer
here that outputs a distribution over the different classes.
Now we're at the most complicated part of the notebook,
where we actually need to implement the output of
the discriminator in the form that we will use for semi-supervised GAN training.
We already have the logits associated with all of the different classes,
where the logits are just the values that drive
the softmax or the inputs that
the softmax gets normalized to form a distribution over the classes.
But to train this classifier as a GAN,
we actually need to have a probability that the input is real, rather than fake.
The softmax gives us the probabilities of all the different real classes and it
also gives us a probability value for the fake class.
We know that the probability of the input being real,
is the sum over all the probabilities of the real classes.
What we want to do now,
is find a value of the logits that we could plug into a sigmoid.
If we wanted to use that sigmoid as a traditional GAN discriminator,
if we want the output of the sigmoid to be the probability
that the input is real rather than fake.
So we've got an expression for the probability we want,
in terms of softmax logits,
we've got to figure out how to rearrange that to be an expression of sigmoid logits.
So you have to do a bit of algebra to solve this part of the notebook.
There's one other trick that's going to be really
important to make this notebook work well,
once you've done your algebra and you've got
an expression for what the logits to the discriminator's sigmoid should be,
you'll need to actually figure out how to implement
the expression for those logits in a numerically stable way.
Your expression should have a log-sum-exp in it somewhere.
And it turns out that log-sum-exp can run into a lot of different problems.
If you should think about what happens if you feed
a very large value into
the log-sum-exp function somewhere and what might happen when you do that.
You should also think about what might happen if you feed nothing but
very negative values for
all the different entries in the vector that you're going to pass to the log-sum-exp.
If either of those things happens,
the naive implementation of log-sum-exp can go wrong.
In the code comments here,
we've explained that there is a trick where you
can subtract the max off of the vector that you
want to compute the log-sum-exp of and move that max and add it outside the log-sum-exp.
If you look at the algebra,
the two forms of the log-sum-exp,
with the max pulled outside and with the max left alone,
those are analytically equivalent to each other.
But, if you think about the two different cases we highlighted,
where some of the values are very extreme,
you'll see that one of them could have numerical problems and the other one avoids a lot
of these numerical problems and using
the stable version will make your classifier perform really a lot better.