After you've implemented everything,
when you run the notebook,
Cell 18 is where most of the action happens.
You can see it print out the Epoch number over time,
and then about 45 seconds after each Epoch starts,
it should print out the classifier training accuracy,
the classifier test accuracy and the amount of time that the last step took.
You can use this to get an idea of how much things like
the size modal players affect the runtime of your notebook.
You should also see the time per Epoch,
which is maybe a little bit more useful for gauging
how long it will be before you see the next batch of samples.
At the end of each Epoch, you should also see the samples coming up.
Every time you run this notebook,
you'll get slightly different results.
The run that I'm showing here is maybe a little bit worse than average,
just so that you don't necessarily set too high of a target for yourself.
As we scroll through the history of what comes out of the training process,
you can see that over time the samples should become more recognizable as digits.
And also you should see that both the training accuracy
and the test accuracy increase over time, and eventually plateau.
After a while, we should start to see that
the training accuracy is quite a lot higher than the test accuracy.
This is because we're using so few label training examples.
It's a lot of work for the classifier to manage to generalize accurately.
On this run through the notebook,
I found that the accuracy peaked at about 69% on the test set.
And in a real application,
you shouldn't look at the test accuracy at every time step like this.
You should use a validation set to decide when to stop and then look at the test set.
But in order to run this notebook faster,
we only wanted to compute two different values,
train and test accuracy.
In general, you should see that you achieve a peak around this kind of value.
It should be somewhere between like 68 to 71 or 72%
accuracy.I have seen a wide range of values every time I rerun it.
You should also see that you have some kind of
recognizable but not necessarily high quality digits at the end of training.
This set up has mostly been optimized to get
good semi-supervised learning performance rather than to get good samples.
Getting really good samples is actually a lot harder than getting
good semi-supervised test accuracy.
It's one of the reasons that I think this is one of
the more useful things we can teach you about GANs at Udacity.
You can easily use GANs to do semi-supervised learning,
even if the learning process is not all that stable,
even if the images at the end are not all that great.
The images just need to be good enough to
give the classifier a little bit of extra practice.
And then it can begin to bring its test accuracy
up and be useful for you as a classifier.
If you look at the learning curves,
you should see that the training set accuracy goes up
really fast and eventually levels off somewhere near perfect.
You'll see that the test accuracy actually levels off a lot earlier.
But it's still much higher than it would be down around the 50% mark,
if we were actually not using semi-supervised learning.
All right, that's the end of the solution to the semi-supervised GAN notebook.
You've seen that you have a really powerful tool for regularizing classifiers.
And don't forget that in this notebook,
we've simplified things so that
the whole process runs in 25 minutes once you have it set up.
If you want to get more performance,
don't forget that there is also the GitHub repository linked at the end of the notebook,
where we show you how to get above 94% accuracy on this task.
This code is very easy to adapt and you can go and take it and apply it to any task where
you don't have enough labels and you'd
still like to build a train classifier that generalizes really well.
So, I hope this is useful to you and I hope you take it and go and do great things.