All right. Now we can dive in and start looking
at how we actually build this semi-supervised GAN.
At the start of this notebook we have a lot of boilerplate code.
We go through some standard imports that make
sure we have things like tensorflow and numpy.
We set up a directory to make sure that we have a place to put all of our data.
And, we have a cell that will go ahead and download the data for you.
And, just show up progress bars that downloads it.
Next, we have some code that actually sets up the data set itself.
Will actually, load the dataset out of the downloaded file,
will re-scale the features to the range negative one to positive one,
will plot a few of the examples so that you can look at
them and see what kind of data you're training on.
The dataset class is the first place that's really interesting to you for this notebook.
Where, you don't actually need to implement anything here
but you need to understand carefully what's going on.
We have this dataset class that represents both a training set,
the validation set and the test set.
For this notebook, we're going to be badly behaved and just disregard the validation set.
When you make a real product or research project,
you should use the validation set to guide
your development efforts and help you choose your hyper parameters and so on.
Here, just to make this exercise go a bit faster,
we're going to cut to the chase and just plot the tests set accuracy.
So, you are going to see exactly what you've accomplished in half an hour or
less of time running on
the GPU rather than how it separately calculate the validation set.
The issue that's most important for you to understand
is that Street View House Number dataset
is essentially fully labeled or
at least the portion of it that we're using for this network is fully labeled.
But, we were to learn about semi-supervised learning.
For semi-supervised learning you don't actually have access to all the labels.
So, what we're going to do is we're going to pretend that we don't have all these labels.
Specifically, we're going to use this label mask variable in
the dataset class to keep track of which labels
we're going to pretend we have and which labels are going to pretend we don't have.
We're going to restrict ourselves to train with only 1000 labeled examples.
That's a very tiny fraction of the actual number of
examples that we have available and labeled.
But we're going to see that we're able to learn from unlabeled examples,
if we ignore their label and just pretend that those weren't available.
The main function that you'll use to access the data set class is this batches method.
You just need to specify the batch size that you want and it will
yield an iterable set of batches that you can just go straight through.
You use the which set argument to request
either the training set or the test set or the validation set that we don't actually use.
We've already set up all of the calls for this method for
you but it's useful to you to understand what it's doing.
One of the wrinkles of this method is that depending on whether
we are looking at the training set or the test set,
we will either return or not return a set of label
masks that tell you whether you can use a particular label for training or not.
In the case of the training set,
we will actually include these label masks.
In all the other cases,
we will not include those label masks.
Because, when we evaluate the accuracy on the test set,
we actually want to check the accuracy for every single example.
So there's no point in having a label mask.