Now that we've defined both our generator model and our discriminator model,
it's time to define the loss functions,
that will actually tell them what they should do when they start learning.
To make the notebook a little bit more convenient,
we've set up these size multipliers for you.
You've got one for the generator and one for the discriminator.
They're just numbers that we multiply by
some other hard-coded number to decide
the size of each layer on both the generator and the discriminator.
If you set these to small values like two or four,
then you won't get very good accuracy,
but the notebook should run a little bit faster.
So you can use those set to small values during the debugging stage,
and then set them back to 32 and 64 when you want to
actually reproduce the accuracy values that we tell you you ought to be able to get.
We've actually gone ahead and run the generator and the discriminator for you.
But we should look at these quickly so that you know what we're doing on your behalf.
And you can do it again yourself,
when you do this in a real project.
First off, we run the generator.
We call it on the input placeholder that we set up
where we'll feed random noise later on as the input to the generator.
By running the generator,
we get some samples that we can use as input to the discriminator later on.
Next we run the discriminator on the real data.
We can unpack all the outputs to the discriminator to get
things like the probability that the input is real,
the logits for the softmax that tells
us which of the classes is present in the real data,
and we can also get the logits for
the sigmoid that tells us whether the input is real or fake.
Finally, we also pull out the features that
we are going to use from one of the last hidden layers of the discriminator,
and we're going to use those for the feature matching loss later on.
Next, you run the discriminator again.
This time, we apply it to the samples rather than to the real data.
There's a few different important things to look at here.
The first is that we're now going to enable reuse for the variable scope.
This is a tensorflow feature where we don't need to
actually allocate the variables that define the weights and biases of the model again.
When we call the discriminator function for a second time,
it's going to ask for the same variable names as it asked for before.
And so by consulting the variable scope,
we can recover the variables that we already made in the first call to the discriminator,
and that will make sure that we train one discriminator with one set of weights,
instead of training one discriminator that looks at
the real data and one discriminator that looks at the fake samples.
The other thing we should think about here that's a little bit funny
is that there's batch normalization inside the discriminator.
In the first case, we call the discriminator on the real data and
compute all of its batch normalization statistics on the real data.
So we compute the mean of all the features on the real data,
we subtract that off,
we compute the standard deviation of the features on the real data,
and we divide by that to get a standard deviation of 1.
And then we make a separate call to the discriminator,
where we run it again this time purely on samples from the generator,
and recompute different values of all those batch normalization statistics.
So in a way, we're actually running two different functions here.
One function that's normalized using real statistics.
One function that's normalized using fake statistics.
This seems very counter-intuitive,
but the authors of the DCGAN paper found that this works really well.
If you look at the paper,
"Improved techniques for training GANs,"
we come up with a few alternatives that are a little bit less weird,
but all of them work about the same in practice,
even though some of them are more or less weird or more or less difficult to implement.
The next task for you is to implement the d_loss variable.
This variable needs to end up containing the loss for the discriminator.
We've said earlier that we're studying semi-supervised learning in this notebook,
and this is where the semi-supervised part happens.
We're going to add together two different loss functions.
One that's unsupervised and one that's supervised.
And the combination of those two losses will make the learning algorithm semi-supervised.
The first loss is the unsupervised loss.
The loss for the GAN problem where we want to tell the difference
between real data and fake samples that came from the generator.
We're going to do that by taking the logit for the sigmoid for the discriminator.
This logit gives us
the unnormalized log probability that the data is real rather than fake.
And we're going to set up a cross entropy loss for that binary classification problem.
Next, the second loss that we're going to add onto this first one,
is the supervised loss.
We're going to use a multiclass cross entropy loss to make sure that the softmax over
classes gets reshaped to output
the right distribution over classes and choose the correct class for each example.
When you implement the supervised loss,
it's very important to remember to use the label mask variable that we pass in.
The label mask variable is a vector that has length batch size.
So it has one entry for every example in the mini-batch.
Every entry of the label mask variable is either a 0 or 1.
If it's zero, it,
means that you should ignore the label for that example.
We have all the labels.
But in order to study semi-supervised learning performance,
we need to pretend that some of them are missing.
Later on, you could try experimenting with ignoring
this label mask variable and seeing if you can actually obtain a higher accuracy.
But when you're working in the main semi-supervised learning part,
you should be sure that you don't actually
use any of the labels that we're asking you to mask out.
After you've added up both the costs for the discriminator,
it's time to move on and build the cost for the generator.
Earlier when we made models like DCGANs,
we saw different losses for the generator than we're going to use now.
Here we're going to use a loss that Tim at
OpenAI invented specifically for semi-supervised learning.
Instead of trying to make the classifier make a mistake,
the generator is actually going to try to output features that are on average similar
to the features that are found by applying the real data to the discriminator.
So, up above, we pulled out the features from the last hidden layer of the discriminator.
We want to take their average and make
sure that the absolute value of the difference between
the average features on the data and
the average features on the samples is as small as possible,
and that will be the only loss that we use for the generator.
That loss tends not to work quite as
well in terms of producing samples that look realistic,
but it works really well for semi-supervised learning.
We don't know for sure why it works better for a semi-supervised learning,
that's mostly an empirical finding.
One thing we can say is that it seems a little bit more like this loss
should cause stable learning than some of the other losses that we use,
because it gives a specific target for where the generator ought to go.
Another thing we can see that might explain why these samples don't look quite as good,
is that it doesn't say exactly how every single example should change individually.
It just says what the average value of the features in the mini-batch should be.
But you can see how if you use more and more features and more and more data,
this is just a kind of moment matching in an adversarially learned space.
So, it should eventually force recovery of the correct data distribution.
Any loss in sample quality is just
due to the fact that we're using finite sizes for everything.
We finish this section with a little bit of boilerplate code that just
takes the argmax across the mini-batch of logits,
in order to tell which class is being
chosen by the classifier for each entry in the mini-batch.
We keep track of how many of those predictions are
correct and we make sure that we also have
a variable that only penalizes
the classifier for missing values where the label is available.
That will enable us to keep track of the error on the label training examples later on.