Finally, we compute the mean absolute difference between these two sets of moments,
and we use that as the loss for the generator.
That will encourage the generator to make sure that all of the future values in
the discriminator have approximately the same average value,
regardless of whether the discriminator is run on the input or run on generated samples.
Over time, this will force the generated samples to become very
similar to data samples and have all of the statistics be the same.
If any of the statistics don't match,
the discriminator can learn to pay attention to
different statistics in order to find the difference between the two distributions.
We also asked you to implement
the learning algorithm where we actually minimize each player's cost.
To do this, you first have to understand which variables are associated with each player.
We can get these two separate lists of variables by sorting
the list of all trainable variables into two different lists.
Because we used variable scopes,
we know that all the variables for the discriminator begin with the name,
"Discriminator," and all the variables for the generator
begin with the name, "Generator."
It's also a good idea to check and make sure that we got all of the variables.
Sometimes you might accidentally write a little bit of code
outside of one of these scopes and you might overlook something.
So we have an assert to make sure that all of
the trainable variables belong to one of these lists or the other.
The next part of that we asked you to implement is
the actual learning roles for each of the two players.
In both cases, you simply use the AdamOptimizer that's built into tensorflow and you
parse through the learning rate and Beta1 parameters
that have been provided earlier in the notebook.
It's important that each player
minimizes the loss with respect to that player's parameters.
So when we call Adam on the loss for the discriminator,
we ask it to optimize only the variables associated with the discriminator.
And likewise when we call Adam on the loss for the generator,
we ask it to optimize only the variables associated with the generator.
If we didn't include these var_list arguments,
Adam would optimize all the trainable variables by default.